Preliminary Inventory to the International Council for Educational Development records
Hoover Institution Archives
International Council for Educational Development records
1960-1994
80192
Hoover Institution Archives
487 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box (204.3 linear feet)
Reports, studies, conference papers, minutes, correspondence, memoranda, pamphlets, bulletins, and other printed matter relating to education, rural development, health, and family planning in developing countries.
International Council For Educational Development.
Access
Collection is open for research. Boxes 357-604 are stored off-site. It may be possible to have a limited number of boxes brought to the archives reading room for examination. A minimum of two days notice is required. Please contact the Hoover Institution Archives for further information.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1980.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Historical Note
American institution for the public benefit to advance education worldwide by promoting, sustaining and increasing individual and collective knowledge and understanding of all aspects of educational development in higher education.
Scope and Content of Collection
Reports, studies, conference papers, minutes, correspondence, memoranda, pamphlets, bulletins, and other printed matter relating to education, rural development, health, and family planning in developing countries.
Boxes are numbered 1-240, then 357-604.
Rural development.; Birth control--Developing countries.; Education--Developing countries.; Public health--Developing countries.
- INDEXES (Boxes 1-21)
  - Author index
    - A-E (Box 1)
    - F-I (Box 2)
    - I-P (Box 3)
    - Q-U (Box 4)
    - U-Z (Box 5)
  - Title index
    - A-E (Box 6)
    - E-L (Box 7)
    - M-Z (Box 8)
  - Topical index
    - A (Box 9)
    - A-C (Box 10)
    - C-E (Box 11)
    - E (Box 12)
    - F-H (Box 13)
    - I-M (Box 14)
    - M-R (Box 15)
    - R-T (Box 16)
    - T-W (Box 17)
    - X-Z (Box 18)
  - Countries index
    - A-I (Box 19)
    - I-M (Box 20)
    - M-Z (Box 21)
- COUNTRIES (Boxes 22-118)
  - Afghanistan
    - General, 1973 (Box 22)
    - Program on Agricultural Credit and Cooperatives in Afghanistan, 1971 (Boxes 22-23)
  - Africa
    - Printed material, 1971 (Boxes 23-24)
  - Americas
    - Family planning information - Jamaica, Mexico, Dominican Republic, 1970-1974 (Box 25)
  - Asia
    - Printed material, 1963-1970 (Box 25)
  - Asia / Mideast
    - Family planning program information - Korea, Malaysia, Taiwan, India, Iran, Turkey, Nepal, Morocco, 1973 (Boxes 25-26)
  - Bangladesh
    - Background materials, 1971 (Boxes 26-28)
    - Bangladesh Rural Advancement Committee - Savar Project, 1973 (Box 28)
    - Comilla Project, 1962-1966 (Boxes 28-31)
    - World Bank reports, 1970-1971 (Boxes 31-32)
    - Family planning, 1973-1975 (Box 33)
    - Program materials, 1970-1976 (Boxes 33-34)
    - Sirajganj Project (Box 35)
      - General
      - Contracts, 1976-1977
      - Contract negotiations, 1976
      - Correspondence, 1976
      - Correspondence report, 1976
      - Fee payment / Asian Development Bank, 1977
      - Report / Asian Development Bank Sirajganj, 1975
      - ICED report, 1976
  - Brazil
    - Brazilian Literacy Movement / MOBRAL, 1974 (Boxes 35-36)
    - Literacy and adult education, 1973 (Box 36)
    - Education development, 1974 (Boxes 36-37)
  - Cameroon
    - Background, 1972-1974 (Box 37)
    - Education and rural development reports, 1973 (Boxes 37-38)
  - China
    - Population and family planning, 1974 (Boxes 38-39)
  - Cuba
    - Education revolution, 1971 (Box 39)
  - Benin
    - Dahomey, 1969-1971 (Boxes 39-40)
  - Ecuador / Peru
    - International Bank for Reconstruction and Development, 1973 (Box 40)
  - El Salvador
    - Agricultural management, 1969-1974 (Box 40)
    - Television and educational reform, 1969-1973 (Boxes 40-41)
  - Ethiopia
    - General, 1972 (Boxes 41-42)
    - Haile Sellassie I University, 1966-1969 (Box 43)
    - Writings and drafts, 1971-1977 (Box 43)
    - Chilalo Agricultural Development Unit, 1967-1969 (Boxes 43-45)
  - Ghana
    - General, 1975 (Box 45)
    - Ghana Rural Reconstruction Movement - Case Study, 1977 (Box 45)
    - Commonwealth Education Conference, 1977 (Box 45)
    - International Planned Parenthood Federation, 1972-1974 (Box 46)
  - Guatemala, 1976 (Box 46)
  - Honduras, 1976 (Box 46)
  - India
    - General, 1971 (Boxes 47-50)
    - Case studies, 1969 (Boxes 51-54)
    - Social Work and Research Center, 1977 (Boxes 54-55)
    - Kosbad Project, 1977 (Boxes 55-56)
  - Indonesia
    - Background materials, 1962-1975 (Boxes 56-62)
      - UNICEF, 1977
      - National Assessment of Education Project, 1971-1972
      - External Assistance Agencies proposals, 1962-1975
    - World Bank reports, 1968-1971 (Box 63)
    - Education, 1974-1975 (Box 63)
    - Pendidikan Masyarakat, 1975-1976 (Boxes 64-65)
    - Program materials, 1973-1975 (Boxes 65-67)
  - Iran
    - Printed material, 1971-1977 (Box 67)
  - Ivory Coast, 1970 (Box 68)
  - Jamaica, 1972 (Boxes 68-69)
  - Kenya
    - Background materials, 1968-1971 (Boxes 70-72)
    - Program materials, 1970-1971 (Box 73)
  - Korea (South)
    - General, 1970 (Boxes 73-75)
    - Case studies, 1968-1970 (Boxes 75-78)
    - Helping the Rural Poor Project
      - General, 1979 (Box 78)
      - Community Based Integrated Rural Development - CBIRD
        - General, 1977 (Boxes 78-79)
        - Correspondence, 1979 (Box 79)
        - VB report (Box 79)
  - Latin America, 1968-1975 (Boxes 79-80)
  - Malawi
    - General, 1972 (Box 80)
    - Printed materials, 1971 (Box 81)
    - Report on the Training Requirements of the LLDP, 1972 (Box 81)
    - Lilongwe Land Development Program, 1971-1972 (Box 81)
  - Malaysia
    - General, 1972 (Box 82)
    - United Nations Children's Fund, 1978 (Boxes 82-83)
  - Mali, 1972 (Boxes 83-84)
  - Mauritius, 1971-1975 (Box 84)
  - Mexico
    - Plan Puebla reports, 1970 (Box 85)
    - Plan Puebla draft, 1970 (Box 85)
    - Puebla Project (Boxes 85-86)
      - Armando Puente Berumen, 1970
      - Alvaro Chapapro, 1970
      - Luis Bolanos, 1970
  - Middle East, 1972 (Box 86)
  - Nigeria
    - Development projects, 1969-1970 (Boxes 86-87)
    - Industrial Development Center, 1970-1971 (Box 87)
    - Case studies, 1963-1969 (Boxes 87-88)
  - Pakistan, 1970-1971 (Boxes 88-89)
  - Philippines
    - General, 1975 (Box 90)
    - Background materials (Boxes 90-94)
      - Educational innovations, 1968-1970
      - Project Management staff, 1974-1975
      - Motivator Experiment report, 1970
      - Cendhrra Newsletter, 1970
    - Helping the Rural Poor Project
      - Philippines Outreach Program, 1970 (Box 94)
    - Program materials, 1971 (Boxes 94-96)
  - Senegal / Chad
    - General, 1967-1971 (Box 96)
    - Bureaucracy, Party, and Rural Commercial Reform, 1970 (Box 97)
    - World Bank Economic report, 1971 (Boxes 97-98)
  - Sri Lanka (Ceylon)
    - General, 1979 (Boxes 98-99)
    - Helping the Rural Poor Project - Sarvodaya, 1978-1979 (Box 100)
  - Tanzania
    - General, 1966-1972 (Boxes 100-104)
    - Printed materials, 1969-1972 (Boxes 104-106)
    - Cooperative education, 1970 (Boxes 106-107)
  - Tanzania / Kenya, 1970-1975 (Boxes 107-108)
  - Thailand
    - General, 1972-1976 (Boxes 108-109)
    - International Bank for Reconstruction and Development, 1970-1971 (Box 109)
    - Case studies (Boxes 109-111)
      - School Finance Improvement Project, 1966-1970
    - Community-Based Family Planning Services (Boxes 111-112)
      - Case Study #7, 1978
    - Integrated Development Program, 1975 (Box 112)
    - Helping the Rural Poor Project - Lampang, 1977-1978 (Boxes 112-113)
      - WB Chapter I Revisions PHC, 1978
    - United Nations Children's Fund, 1972-1976 (Boxes 113-114)
  - Uganda
    - General, 1969-1971 (Box 114)
  - Upper Volta (Burkina Faso)
    - Rural Education and Agricultural Development, 1973 (Box 115)
    - International Bank for Education and Development, 1970 (Box 116)
  - Venezuela, 1972-1973 (Boxes 116-117)
  - Western Europe, 1969 (Boxes 117-118)
- TOPICS (Boxes 118-153)
  - Community development, 1972-1974 (Box 118)
  - Developed countries / less developed countries relations, 1974 (Box 118)
  - Education and development, 1969-1973 (Boxes 118-120)
  - Educational financing, 1969-1970 (Boxes 120-121)
  - Educational planning and statistics, 1972-1975 (Boxes 121-125)
  - Green revolution and agricultural production, 1968-1974 (Boxes 125-126)
  - Integrated program, 1969-1975 (Box 127)
  - Integration, 1971-1974 (Box 127)
  - Land reclamation settlement schemes, 1969-1970 (Box 128)
  - Land tenure / Land reform, 1970 (Box 129)
  - Literacy, 1967-1975 (Boxes 130-132)
  - Irrigation agrarian reform / Valley development projects / Land reclamation settlement schemes, 1965-1970 (Box 133)
  - Manpower, 1963-1968 (Box 134)
  - Mass media, 1973 (Boxes 134-137)
  - Nomadism, 1968 (Box 137)
  - Rural development, 1965-1970 (Boxes 138-140)
  - Rural education, 1970-1975 (Boxes 140-141)
  - Rural employment, 1973-1975 (Boxes 140-141)
  - Rural industries and services, 1969-1972 (Box 142)
  - Secondary / higher education, 1967 (Boxes 142-144)
  - Teacher training, 1966-1971 (Box 145)
  - Unconventional primary / secondary education, 1972 (Boxes 145-146)
  - Village polytechnics, 1968-1972 (Boxes 146-147)
  - Vocational training, 1959-1972 (Boxes 147-148)
  - Voluntary organizations, 1972-1974 (Box 148)
  - Women's programs, 1965-1971 (Boxes 149-150)
  - Youth policy, 1972-1974 (Box 151)
  - Youth programs, 1971 (Boxes 151-153)
- CONFERENCES (Boxes 154-167)
  - Ahmed, Manzoor - miscellaneous documents, 1970-1973 (Box 154)
  - Asian and South Pacific Bureau of Adult Education - Tehran, Iran, 1978 (Box 155)
  - Commonwealth Secretariat. South Asia Symposium on Employment Strategies and Programs - Chandigarh, India, 1976 (Box 155)
  - Economicas Politicas y de Investigacion de las Escuelas Radiofonicas - San Jose, Costa Rica, 1976 (Boxes 155-156)
  - International Seminar on Higher Education - Hiroshima, Japan, 1976 (Box 156)
  - International Association for the Evaluation of Educational Achievement. Conference - Harvard University, 1973 (Boxes 156-157)
  - International Conference on Adult Education, 3d - Tokyo, Japan, 1972 (Box 157)
  - International Conference on Nonformal Education - Paris, France, 1971 (Boxes 157-158)
  - International Seminar on Planning Problems in Rural Education - Paris, France, 1975 (Box 214)
  - International Symposium for Literacy - Persepolis, Iran, 1975 (Box 215)
  - Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development - Paris, France, 1974 (Box 159)
  - Southeast Asia Development Advisory Group - Seoul, South Korea, 1971 (Boxes 159-160)
  - Stanford University Communication Policy and Planning for Education and Development - Stanford, California, 1976 (Boxes 160-161)
  - Tokyo International Symposium - Tokyo, Japan, 1976 (Boxes 161-162)
  - UNICEF, Conference of Ministers on Children and Youth - Lome, Togo, 1972 (Boxes 162-163)
  - UNICEF, Executive Board Session - New York City, 1977 (Boxes 163-164)
  - UNESCO, Structures of Adult Education in Developing Countries - Nairobi, Kenya, 1975 (Box 165)
  - UNESCO, Cooperation Program on Basic Education - Nairobi, Kenya, 1974 (Boxes 165-166)
  - United Nations International Women's Year Conference - Mexico City, Mexico, 1975 (Box 166)
  - World Conference on Agricultural Education and Training - Copenhagen, Denmark, 1970 (Box 166)
- ISSUING AGENCIES (Boxes 167-239)
  - Academy for Educational Development
    - General, 1973 (Boxes 167-168)
    - Instructional technology material, 1972-1976 (Boxes 168-169)
  - Agricultural Development Council, 1972-1977 (Box 169)
  - American Council of Voluntary Agencies for Foreign Service/Technical Assistance Information Clearing House, 1973-1975 (Box 169)
  - American Council on Education / Overseas Liaison Committee, 1973-1975 (Boxes 170-172)
  - Annual reports, 1977 (Boxes 172-174)
  - Canadian International Development Agency, 1971 (Box 174)
  - Center for the Study of Education in Changing Societies, 1973-1975 (Boxes 174-175)
  - Centro Latinoamericano de Educacion de Adultos, 1976-1977 (Box 175)
  - Christian Michelsen Institute, 1970-1973 (Box 175)
  - Commonwealth Secretariat
    - General, 1975-1979 (Boxes 175-176)
    - Alfred Wallace Wood, 1970 (Box 176)
    - Printed materials, 1970-1973 (Boxes 176-178)
    - Youth and development, 1973-1975 (Box 178)
  - Consortium for the Study of Nigerian Rural Development, 1968 (Boxes 178-179)
  - Cornell University - Rural Development Committee, 1974 (Boxes 179-180)
  - East-West Center - University of Hawaii, 1976 (Box 180)
  - Education and World Affairs, 1967-1968 (Boxes 180-181)
  - Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations, 1966-1970 (Box 181)
  - Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations / World Health Organization, 1977-1979 (Box 181)
  - Ford Foundation
    - General, 1973 (Boxes 182-184)
    - Urbanization studies, 1973-1974 (Box 184)
  - Ford Foundation / International Committee on the Management of Population Problems, 1975-1976 (Boxes 184-185)
  - German Foundation for International Development, 1969-1976 (Box 185)
  - German Foundation for International Development / German Foundation for Developing Countries, 1971-1973 (Box 186)
  - Harvard University - Institute for International Development, 1970-1977 (Box 186)
  - India - Ministry of Education and Social Welfare, 1974-1975 (Box 186)
  - Intergovernmental Coordinating Committee for Southeast Asia Regional Cooperation in Family and Population Planning, 1975-1976 (Boxes 186-188)
  - Institute de Recherche et d'Application des Methodes de Developpement, 1971-1973 (Box 188)
  - Institute of Current World Affairs, 1973-1975 (Box 189)
  - Institute of Social Studies, 1973 (Box 190)
  - International Audio-Visual Resource Service, 1974-1976 (Boxes 191-192)
  - International Bureau of Education, 1970-1974 (Boxes 192-193)
  - International Commission on the Development of Education, 1971 (Boxes 193-194)
  - International Development Research Center, 1973-1975 (Box 194)
  - International Development Research Center - Canada, 1975-1976 (Box 195)
  - International Institute for Educational Planning
    - General, 1968-1973 (Boxes 196-198)
    - Cost case studies, 1969-1970 (Boxes 199-201)
  - International Labour Office
    - General, 1973-1979 (Boxes 201-202)
    - World Employment Program / Population and Employment Working Paper Series, 1974 (Box 202)
  - International Monetary Fund Survey, 1976-1977 (Boxes 202-203)
  - Michigan State University
    - General, 1975-1976 (Boxes 203-205)
    - Midwest Universities Consortium for International Activities, 1976 (Box 206)
    - Institution Building and Technical Assistance Methodology, 1976-1977 (Boxes 206-207)
  - Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development
    - General, 1970-1973 (Box 207)
    - Conference on Policies for Educational Growth, 1970 (Box 207)
    - Youth Employment Seminar - Dublin, 1970 April 14-17 (Box 207)
    - Printed material, 1969-1970 (Boxes 207-210)
    - Recurrent education, 1971-1973 (Box 210)
  - Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development. Development Assistance Committee
    - Annual reports, 1968-1974 (Box 211)
    - Population programs, 1968-1970 (Box 211)
  - Overseas Development Administration, 1970-1976 (Boxes 212-213)
  - Pakistan Institute of Development Economics, 1975 (Box 213)
  - Rockefeller Foundation, 1970-1973 (Box 213)
  - Societe d'Etudes pour le Developpement Economique et Social, 1970-1971 (Box 213)
  - Southeast Asian Ministers of Education Organization, 1973-1979 (Boxes 214-216)
  - Stanford International Development Education Center, 1969-1973 (Box 216)
  - Swedish International Development Authority, 1969-1971 (Boxes 216-217)
  - United Nations
    - General, 1969-1973 (Boxes 217-218)
    - Report on Organizational Strategies, 1978-1979 (Boxes 218-219)
  - United Nations Children's Fund
    - General, 1971-1979 (Boxes 219-221)
    - Documentation, 1971-1972 (Boxes 221-222)
    - Progress reports for Africa, 1974-1976 (Box 222)
    - Project proposal for Asia, 1974-1976 (Box 223)
  - United Nations Development Program
    - Governing Council papers, 1970-1971 (Boxes 223-224)
  - United Nations Economic Commission for Africa, 1966-1971 (Box 224)
  - United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization, 1976-1978 (Boxes 224-225)
  - United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization. Regional Center for Functional Literacy in Rural Areas for the Arab States, 1960-1964 (Box 225)
  - United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization. Regional Office for Education in Africa, 1973-1977 (Box 226)
  - United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization. Regional Office for Education in Asia, 1972-1976 (Boxes 226-227)
  - United Nations Research Institute for Social Development, 1968-1976 (Boxes 227-228)
  - United States Agency for International Development, 1970-1977 (Boxes 229-230)
  - United States Government Agencies, 1974-1975 (Boxes 230-231)
  - University of California, 1974 (Boxes 231-232)
  - University of Massachusetts Center for International Education, 1975-1977 (Box 232)
  - University of Nairobi Institute for Development Studies, 1974-1975 (Boxes 232-233)
  - University of Ottawa Institute for International Cooperation, 1968-1975 (Box 233)
  - University of Wisconsin Land Tenure Center, 1971-1976 (Boxes 234-235)
  - World Bank
    - General, 1969-1973 (Boxes 235-236)
    - Projects, 1970-1971 (Boxes 236-237)
    - Publications, 1975-1978 (Box 237)
  - World Bank Group, 1974-1975 (Box 237)
  - World Council of Churches, 1974 (Boxes 238-239)
  - World Education, 1974-1976 (Box 239)
  - Yale University, 1975-1978 (Box 239)
- EMPTY (Boxes 241-356)
- UNSORTED (Boxes 357-421)
- SYSTEMS STUDY OF HIGHER EDUCATION (Boxes 422-440)
  - Files of Nell P. Eurich (project director) (Boxes 422-432)
  - Clippings and background papers (Boxes 432-435)
  - Files of James A. Perkins (chairman of ICED) (Boxes 435-438)
  - Publications of study (Box 438)
  - Background materials on Australia (Boxes 439-440)
- ACCESS TO HIGHER EDUCATION STUDY (Boxes 440-446)
  - General (Boxes 440-446)
  - Publications of study (Box 446)
- HIGHER EDUCATION FOR DEVELOPMENT STUDY (Boxes 447-451)
  - General (Boxes 447-451)
  - Publications of study (Box 451)
- YOUTH, EDUCATION AND EMPLOYMENT STUDY (Boxes 451-456)
- PRESIDENT'S COMMISSION ON FOREIGN LANGUAGE AND INTERNATIONAL STUDIES (Boxes 457-462)
  - General (Boxes 457-462)
  - Published report (Box 462)
- NATIONAL COUNCIL ON FOREIGN LANGUAGES AND INTERNATIONAL STUDIES (Boxes 462-466)
- UNSORTED (Boxes 467-604)